Hey Folks, the series of comparison of HDFCGO Optima Secure Plus
continues and today I am going to
compare this plan
with its equivalent plan and that is
Elevate Plan of ICIC LBRD. Both the plans are
equivalent plans.  The features are almost the same
in both the plans.  We have to see
what their premiums say?
What do the fundamentals of the insurance company
say and
what will be the differences in the features of both the plans.
I will tell you in full detail.
What is inclusion?  What are exclusions?
What are the features?  What are premiums?
What are the discounts?  And
what are the basic features of this plan?
You have to watch this video till the end and if you have come to
Insurance Seva for the first time then
subscribe to Insurance Seva.  Press the bell icon
and you
can also share the video with your friends and relatives.
[Music]
So comparing health insurance plans
is my favorite topic.  But
even in this favorite topic, I will first
compare the fundamentals of insurance companies.
Because when you go to the hospital,
you neither remember any features nor the
premium.  At that time,
only one thing comes to my mind that
somehow this claim should be settled and I should get well and go back to
my home.  So first of all let's talk about
comparison, here I have IC LBA
Elevate and HDFC Argo Optima Secure Plus.  Let us look at the
fundamentals of the company.
Claim settlement ratio of 97% is claimed by
IC LBR and 98% by HDFC Ago
Incident claim ratio of 82% is claimed by IC LBR and
85% by HDFC Ago Solvency ratio of 2.69 is
of ICIC LBR and 2.2 is of HDFC Ago
15000 plus network hospitals are of IC LBR
and 16,000 network hospitals are
of HDFC Ago.  The claim process will be
online under both the policies.  It will be hassle free.  So
fundamentally if I see, both the
policies of both the companies are more and less same.  There
is a slight difference of 2-3% between the two companies.  Now
[nasal sound] let's talk about
what the features inside these two plans say?  What special thing was added to these
two plans due to which they became
revolutionary and unique.  So first of all let's
talk about Optima Secure
Plus.  So, although A B C D rider is
already there in Optima Secure also,
but here also you can take add on cover.
Asthma, blood pressure, cholesterol and
diabetes cover will be available from 31 days
after adding this add-on by paying additional premium.  Same you have
Jump Start inside the Elevate plan at ICC Lumbard.
There also you can get coverage for asthma, blood pressure,
cholesterol, diabetes and obesity for
31 days.  Now let's talk about
some more unique features,
Optima Secure Plus has added infinite benefits.
They have replaced the Plus benefit
with the Infinite benefit.
Now whatever time you have left will increase 100%
and will keep increasing throughout your life.  A
very good feature to beat inflation, almost all companies have
now introduced it.  The ICC LBA
already has it.  Power Booster is the same.
Your increase will be assured 100% of the time and will continue to
increase for infinite time i.e. unlimited time.
Your base sum assured will keep getting added to your policy as long as you run the policy.
Secure Benefit
is within Optima Secure Plus.  Buy one get one
free.  Will take a policy of Rs 10 lakh.
You will get a cover of Rs 20 lakh from Day One.  If you take a policy of Rs 50 lakh,
you will get a cover of Rs 1 crore from day one.
You should take a policy of Rs 2 crore.
You will get a cover of Rs 4 crore from Day One.
You will not get this cover or this benefit in ICC Lobard's
Elevate plan.  Protect
benefit that covers the entire list of consumable items.  That means it
reduces the burden on your pocket.  Same
Claim Protector is an add on.
Inside ICC Lobbard's Elevate Plan.  It
is inbuilt here i.e. it
is inbuilt in Optima Secure Plus and Claim Protector
is an add on cover inside Elevate.
You can get this cover by paying a little extra money.
Limitless cover and
infinite care are both the same.  But a little
different is Limitless Cover.  Limitless cover
is available in Optima Secure Plus.  You can take unlimited claims once in your lifetime.
In policies up to ₹50 lakh.  Take a policy of Rs 50 lakh.
Take the one above that.  So you can take
unlimited claim twice in your life for any
amount as per your choice.
You can take Infinite Care only once in your life.  No matter
how many lakhs
your policy is worth.
Now let's talk about Optima Well Being.
Optima Wellbeing which is an OPD cover.
In select cities,
you will get it under Optima Secure Plus and
in ICC Labrad Elevate, you will get OPD worth ₹5,000
with add-on cover.  A Serious
Illness Booster which is
an add-on cover added to Optima Secure Plus.
[nasal noise] If you
add this cover, there are a few select
diseases.  There are some listed critical
illnesses which are covered and if you fall ill,
you will get double cover.  That means, in a policy of Rs 10 lakh,
Secure Benefit of Rs 10 lakh and Serious
Illness Booster of Rs 10 lakh will also be added to it.  That means
Devon will cover 30 lakhs.
This benefit is not currently available within ICC Lamb's
Elevate plan.  But
inside Elevate you can take the benefit of BeFit.
Which has OPD as well as
many wellness programs.  There are a lot of
memberships.  They can add all those things.
Durable medical equipment can
also be covered as an add-on cover under ICC LBA's Elevate
plan.  So [ __ ] my
next slide is the discount
slide.  It is very important to know
how much discount I am going to get on my money.
So first of all we will talk about Optima Secure Plus.  There
is a lifetime discount of 5%.
If your age is 35 years or less.
Enter into this plan.  You will
get an instant discount of 5% which
you will continue to get for life time.
You will not get any such discount in ICC Low's Elevate plan.
But in the Elevate plan,
you will get a discount on civil score.
If your civil score is above 800, you can
get a discount of up to 15%.   If it is
less than 800 then you will get a little less but
you will get civil score discount.
You will not get the Civil Score discount
in Optimus Secure Plus.
Favourable claim experience discounts are
available under Optimus Secure Plus
starting at 21% and going up to 18% on renewal.
Suppose you port your policy
and there
is no claim in your policy in the last 2 years, then
you will get an instant discount of 21% which will be
followed by 18% and will continue thereafter as per the
claim history.
You will not get any discount in the new policy
but after 2 years you will get discount on favourable claim.  There
is no such discount within the ICC LB Elevate plan.  There is a
wellness discount that goes up to 30%.
Walk a few steps per day,
keep yourself healthy and you get a discount.
You will get loyalty discount
in Optimyor Plus.  If you
are an existing customer of HDFC ARGO and have any HDFCGO
policy, you will
get an instant discount of 2.5%.
This discount is not available in ICC LB.  Early
renewal discount is available under ICC LBA's Elevate
plan.
If you renew your policy 30 days in advance, then
long term discount of 2.5% is available
in both the policies and in both the policies
you get the facility to pay premium for 1 year, 2 years, 3 years, 4 years and 5
years.
You get convenience.  You
can take a long term policy by availing a discount.  It's
time for the basic features of this plan.
Let's see
what the comparison is in the basic features.  First of all sum
assured 10 lakh, 15 lakh, 20 lakh, 25 lakh,
50 lakh, 1 crore, 2 crore.  Here's what's
inside the Optima Secure Plus.  The ICC Low
Elevate plan offers a few more options.
There is also an option of Rs 5 lakh, Rs 7.5 lakh
and also an option of Rs 3 crore and unlimited.  That means,
take unlimited sum assured and all the hassle will end.
Entry age ranges from 18 years to 60 years.
This is where the Optima Secure Plus gets
compromised a bit.  It becomes limited
for some age groups.
You will not get this plan above 60.  From 18 years
to No Limit, ICC is within Laborde's Elevate
plan.  A person of any age can
enroll in the policy.  Policy
Tenure: As usual, I have already told you that a
policy can be taken for up to 5 years.  There will be
no variants.  In the family size, Optimus
Secure is slightly ahead.  Four adults and six
kids can get the policy.  There will be a
policy only for ICBA two adults and three kids.  Remortgage is a very most most most most
important feature
of any health insurance policy, rather it would be wrong to
call it a [nasal sound] feature.
These are inbuilt terms and
conditions and are very crucial terms
and conditions.  The actual ROM rent will be
inside your Optima Secure Plus.   That means there will be no
capping.  You
can downgrade to a single private AC room to
reduce the premium.  Whereas
in ICM's Elevate plan you will
get inbuilt single private AC room.  It can be
downgraded as well as
upgraded.  I'm coming
to the next slide [nasal sound]
and on the next slide my
ICU ICCU copayment is none
under both the policies.  Pre-
hospitalization and post-hospitalization are
also very important features.  This
is a very important addon.  60 Days Pre
Hospitalization and 180 Days Post
Hospitalization up to sum assured Optima
Secure Plus 90 Days Pre Hospitalization
180 Days Post Hospitalization up to sum
assured ICC Lambda Elevate Plan.  Here the
pre becomes 30 days extra.
Modern Treatment Robotic Surgeries There
is no capping.  E-consultation is listed
for 53 critical illnesses in Optima Secure
Plus and
you can avail tele-consultation as an add-on under Lumbard's Elevate plan.
Unlimited restoration for the same person and same
illness will be inbuilt in both the plans.  It
is beans.  Road Ambulance Up to Sum
Assured There is no capping sublimit.  Air
ambulance is inbuilt in Optima Secure Plus.
Hospitalization at ₹5 lakh
but
you have to take add-on in ICC Lombard Elevate Plan but the amount you will get will remain the same at ₹5
lakh.  No Claim Bonus The
infinite benefit in Optima Secure is the
No Claim Bonus.  100% assured your lift will
increase.  But ICC will go to LB at 20% yearly
and up to 100%.  Even if there is a claim,
it will be different from the power booster if there is no claim.  That
means you will get this also and if
you have taken power booster add on then you will get that also.
Home care domiciliary treatment up
to some assured waiting period of PED is
already disease.  If there is a pre-existing disease, then the coverage
in both the policies is 36 months, which is the
regulatory guideline.  Talk about annual
[nasal sound] health checkups.
ICC is an add-on cover
in Lombard's Elevate plan but will be
inbuilt in Optima Secure Plus.
Alternative treatment
is up to sum assured cover in both policies.  Maternity
cover is available in both the policies.  But both the
policies come with add-on cover.
You can add parenthood.
In Optima Secure Plus you will get ₹500, ₹1 lakh, ₹1.5 lakh, ₹2 lakh after 2 years.  You
can add as per your choice and your need.
ICC LBA with add on is in the plan.   The
maximum limit will be ₹1 lakh.  After 2 years it can be
reduced to one year.
Wellness program up to 30% ICC
is available within LBD's Elevate plan which is
not available in Optima Secure Plus.  Deductible
options are available only in Optima Secure Plus.
Elevate doesn't have it.  There are multiple
deductible options.  You can reduce your premium substantially by taking a deductible of ₹25,500, ₹1 lakh, ₹
2 lakh, ₹3 lakh and ₹5 lakh.
So box now the time has come to
complete this video and I will complete it
with premiums.  It is very important to
check the premium to see
how much it will burden your pocket or whether it
suits your pocket.  I will take Optima Secure
Plus first, it is time for 10 lakhs.  The
address is Delhi NCR.  40
years is an age.  The premium for Two Adult Two Kit will be
₹34,697.
Almost all things are added in it.
We have not added any add-on cover to it.
This will be the premium at the age of 46.
₹42,123
and for the same cover at the same location at the
age of 51 years the premium will be ₹53,855.
Now let us compare this with SC Elevate
plan, then at the age of 40, the same
premium will come to ₹26,692,
which is almost ₹6 to
₹7,000 more economical than Optima Secure.  If
compared at 46 years, then ₹35,663 will
come under Elevate plan.  There
are ₹42,000 there.  So the difference comes to approximately ₹6,500.
₹44,923.51 is of
Elevate plan at the age of 1 year.  There are
₹53,855 there.
So here the difference is approximately
₹7,000.  So if you compare premium wise
then IC LBD Elevate plan
is economical and in Elevate plan
I have added all those add on covers which
are inbuilt in Optima Secure.  Only then will
a correct comparison be made.  So
what is the overall conclusion of this?  The overall
conclusion is that if we talk about
fundamentals, then if I have to
say which company is better in fundamentals, then
here HDFC ARGO is comparatively better.
Now if we talk about the features of IC LBRD, then
many features are more or less same and if we talk about add-on
cover, then the add-on cover in LBRD
is a little more as compared to
Optima Secure. If we come to the premium, then
premium wise ICIC LBRD
is comparatively economical. If I
talk about HDFC Ergo's Optima Secure,
maternity
is covered in both the plans.  Rest you see
which plan suits you as per your needs.
Rest, if you want to know any query regarding these two plans, or if
you want to ask anything, you can
ask me in the comment box.  I will meet
you in my next video.  Till then
Jai Hind, Jai